STEVEN ANDRYCHUK

Address: Helsinki, Finland Email: elliottcarlisle1002@gmail.com

A dedicated full stack developer with 6 years of hands-on experience creating microservices, APIs, and web applications. Possessed a broad knowledge of tech stack, including Python, C#, .NET and JavaScript. Worked on different kinds of projects handling everything from product ideation to development, maintenance and ultimately client acquisition.

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2022 - MAR 2023

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER, UNSCHOOLER | REMOTE

- Structured the store and added thunk middlewares for APIs using **Reduxjs toolkit** for a better performance and code optimization.
- Built the forecast dashboard for an Al platform with **Angular**, **angular-data-grid**, integrated 3rd party services including **GA** and **Mixpanel**.
- Served as the lead engineer and conducted code review and mentored other developers.
- •Contributed to building e-commerce website by improving efficiency by 20% with GraphQL and **Apollo**.
- Built and maintained software services and UI components with Angular,
 TypeScript, Microsoft Azure, RxJS and Django.
- Participated in building an NFT marketplace with React, TypeScript, MUI and ethers.is.
- Implemented new features including OAuth of an educational platform (React / Express / PostgreSQL / Firebase).
- Improved the performance of the market place by 30% leveraging optimization techniques and deployed it into **AWS**.

- Created a mobile application to manage orders for patients using React Native.
- Designed and implemented the auditing system of the company using Vue,
 TypeScript and Django.

MAR 2019 - DEC 2021

BACKEND DEVELOPER, SCOPIC | US, REMOTE

- Developed a real time communication platform within the company (React / Express / MongoDB / EasyRTC / Bootstrap).
- Implemented the task board for a company using Laravel Livewire.
- Created an automated documentation system using Vue and Element Plus.
- Planned website development, converting mock-ups into usable web presence with **HTML**, **JavaScript**, **Angular**, **React** and **Vue.is**.
- Collaborated with the external engineering and design team to integrate the APIs and build the UI.
- Wrote unit and e2e tests for APIs, components and UI flow in several applications (Enzyme / Cypress / Jest).
- Designed and implemented API endpoints for the admin panel of the online learning site (**Node / Express / REST**).
- Participated in the team project for building customer-facing web applications and MVPs using **React**, **PostgreSQL** and **Node.js**.
- Found bugs in the beta version and improved original mechanism to enhance search functionality (Laravel / Elastic Search).
- Translated designs into pixel perfect responsive UI by collaborating with the designer using **React**, **TypeScript**, **Tailwind** and **MUI**.

MAR 2017 - FEB 2019

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER, CLEVEROAD | TALLINN, ESTONIA

- Upgraded the legacy code and UI of the ERP system using React, Bootstrap and SASS.
- Built the video browsing platform using **Next.js** and video streaming technology.

- Involved in several team projects and got used to the agile methodology.
- Built the admin system of the financial agency using **MERN** stack.
- Performed website development for clients in diverse fields such as health care, education, fintech and so on.
- Kept up-to-date with the latest technologies through learning, research and selfdevelopment.

EDUCATION

SEP 2012 - FEB 2017

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF EASTERN FINLAND

JOENSUU, KUOPIO, EASTERN FINLAND, FINLAND

SKILLS

Languages

C#, JAVA, JavaScript, Solidity, TypeScript, Python, PHP

• Frameworks/Libraries

Django, .NET Core, Web3 , .NET, Fast API, Angular, React, Laravel, Next.js, Express.js, Spring Boot, Vue, Material UI

Storage

MySQL, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, GraphQL

STRENGTH

- Communication
- Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- Flexibility
- Time management